# Avishek Mazumder (1) Featured

Java Developer seeking assignments in Software Development, Application Programming, Program Management, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, Core Java, Servlets, JSP, JDBC, Hibernate, Spring Framework, Spring Boot, Oracle SQL, Maven



Current Designation: Analyst, Software Developer Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: TIAA GBS Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: Pune Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [IT]

Pref. Location: Canada, Pune

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Analyst, Software Developer, Application Programming, Program Management, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, Core Java, Servlets, JSP, JDBC, Hibernate, Spring

Framework, JSF, Oracle SQL, Maven, ANT, SDLC, Software Development, Agile, Struts

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 22-Nov-20 Last Modified: 22-Nov-20

# Summary

Over 5 years of experience in the development of Web & Enterprise applications using JAVA and Spring Technologies. Hands on experience in Core Java, Servlets, JSP, JDBC, Hibernate, Spring Framework, Spring Boot, JSF, Struts.

Sound knowledge of RDBMS. Competent in writing Oracle SQL queries. Acquainted with MongoDB.

Hands on experience with using Maven and ANT for project management

Experienced in Agile SDLC methodology

Acquainted with DevOps. Acquainted with implementing CICD using Teamcity and Jenkins.

Sound knowledge of Data Structures.

Experienced in the domain of Investment banking and its working.

Cohesive team worker, quick and independent learner, with good communication and interpersonal skills.

# Work Experience

TIAA GBS as Analyst, Software Developer

Feb 2018 to Till Date

Working on spring boot microservice meant to process files and plans for participants of an insurance client

Role: Developer

Environment: Java, Spring boot, Rest Webservices, Rabbit MQ, Mongo DB

Tools: intelliJ, MongoChef, Rabbit MQ management console, Git Bash. TortoiseGit, Swagger Editor, Swagger Hub

TIAA Global Business Services as Software Analyst

Feb 2018 to Feb 2018

Infosys Limited as Senior Systems Engineer

Sep 2015 to Feb 2018

Project 3: TCP

Description:

This application is a backend java process based tool responsible for publishing deal ticket information of trades booked from various front-office applications in xml format.

Spring provides DI. JAXB is used for unmarshalling and marshalling of xml messages.

Oracle is used as data store.

SOAP webservice call is performed to communicate with another external application.

Role: Team Member (Developer)

Environment: Java 1.6, Oracle 11g, Tomcat

Tools: Eclipse, Toad, XmlSpy

Responsibilities

Development of code as per requirement of the content of xml to be published

Development of code for the purpose of enhancement requirement raised through JIRA.

Debugging and root cause analysis of defects when raised

Project 2: Schema Compliance Checker Period: December 2016 to January 2017

Description:

The web application performs XSD validation (Using JAXB) of deal ticket XML of trades generated within a certain date range in the TCP DB (refer above project) and generates an excel report of validation errors for each deal ticket XML along with certain other data.

It is a JEE application where Spring provides DI and MVC framework. Hibernate serves as ORM framework to communicate with Oracle DB (TCP data store).

The application has ability to handle reporting for around 80000 to 90000 trades at one go which is made possible by hibernate batching and SXSSF API of Apache POI for excel sheet generation.

Role: Developer

Environment: Java 1.8, Tomcat Tools: Eclipse Juno, Toad, XmlSpy,

Responsibilities:

Designed the architecture of the application

Researched and decided upon all relevant technologies to be used by the application to meet the functional and nonfunctional requirements.

Developed the code for the application from scratch.

Developed and executed Unit Test Cases covering functional and non-functional requirements

Delivered the ready to use version within a span of 5 days.

Project 1: Alpine

Period: April 2016 to December 2016

Description:

The web application is a middle-office investment banking application used to perform trade-order matching for clients. It is a JEE application supported by Spring. Front-end is built upon Struts MVC. Hibernate provides the ORM support. Application also uses JMS to communicate with other systems as well as for some internal communication channel. RMI is also used to communicate among different modules of the application.

Maven is used as the build tool. Oracle DB serves as Data store.

Role: Developer

Environment: Java 1.6, Tomcat

Responsibilities

Developed modules involving coding from front-end using Struts MVC to Hibernate at backend. Implemented RMI functionality within the modules using spring

Developed code for the purpose of enhancements required in the project

Debugging and root cause analysis of defects when raised

Designed test-cases for the enhancements and new modules developed

Execution of test cases and end-to-end testing of the application

# **Education**

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (IT) from West Bengal University of Technology (WBUT) in 2015

#### IT Skills

| Skill Name        | Version Last Used Experience |
|-------------------|------------------------------|
| Java , C , Python |                              |
| Oracle 11g SQL    |                              |
| JSF, Struts       |                              |
| Angular js        |                              |
| Tomcat            |                              |

| JEE , JDBC, JAXB                |  |
|---------------------------------|--|
| Spring, spring boot, Spring MVC |  |
| Oracle, MongoDB                 |  |
| JMS,AMQP, RabbitMQ              |  |
| Hibernate, Spring Data          |  |

# Languages Known

| Language | Proficiency | Read | Write | Speak |
|----------|-------------|------|-------|-------|
| English  |             |      |       |       |
| Hindi    |             |      |       |       |
| BENGALI  |             |      |       |       |

# **Projects**

Project Title: ROSS Client: Inhouse

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Jan 2020 - Aug 2020

Role: Programmer Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Team Size: 7

Project Details: Backend file-processing microservice

Project Title: OBR Client: TIAA

Duration: Feb 2018 - May 2019 Nature of Employment: Full Time

Project Location: Pune Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Team Size: 7 Role: Programmer Skill Used: Java 8.0, MongoDB, Spring Boot, Neo4j, Spring Data, Spring Boot Rest

Role Description: Analyse and develop modules

Maintenance of code and fix defects Analysis and timely delivery of user stories

Project Details: Microservices based on Spring Boot rest APIs that facilitates front end to store data to persistence layer

(mongodb) usimg rest service calls.

Project Title: TCP Client: UBS

Duration: Jan 2017 - Till Date Nature of Employment: Full Time Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Project Location: Pune Role: Programmer Team Size: 5

Skill Used: Spring, Hibernate, Core Java, Web Services, JAXB, JAX-WS

Development of code as per requirement of the content of xml to be published Role Description: \*

- Development of code for the purpose of enhancement requirement raised through JIRA.
- Debugging and root cause analysis of defects when raised

Project Details: This application is a backend java process based tool responsible for publishing deal ticket information of trades booked from various front-office applications in xml format.

Spring provides DI. JAXB is used for unmarshalling and marshalling of xml messages.

Oracle is used as data store.

Web service call is performed to communicate with another external application.

Project Title: Schema Compliance Checker

Client: UBS

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Dec 2016 - Jan 2017 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Project Location: Pune Team Size: 3 Role: Programmer

Skill Used: Core Java, Spring Mvc, Hibernate, Apache POI, XML Schema, Sax, JAXB,

Role Description: \* Designed the architecture of the application

Researched and decided upon all relevant technologies to be used by the application to meet the functional and nonfunctional requirements.

Developed the code for the application from scratch.

Project Details: The web application performs XSD validation (Using JAXB) of deal ticket XML of trades generated within a certain date range in the TCP DB (refer above project) and generates an excel report of validation errors for each deal ticket XML

along with certain other data.

It is a JEE application where Spring provides DI and MVC framework. Hibernate serves as ORM framework to communicate with Oracle DB (TCP data store).

The application has ability to handle reporting for around 80000 to 90000 trades at one go which is made possible by hibernate batching and SXSSF API of Apache POI for excel sheet generation.

#### **Affirmative Action**

**Work Authorization** 

Category: General

Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time